Guide to the Rose Cosgrove County Longford Ladies Auxiliary Papers AIA.061
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Rose Cosgrove County Longford Ladies Auxiliary Papers
1949-2007
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Cosgrove, Rose
AIA.061
3 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, 2 oversize flat boxes, 2 small artifact boxes, and 1 folder in shared housing
Rose Cosgrove (1908-2009) was a leading member of the County Longford Association and the County Longford Social Club of New York. This collection consists of materials pertaining to the County Longford Ladies Auxiliary, the County Longford Association, the United Irish Counties Association, and other Irish American organizations based in the greater New York City area. Materials include photographs, artwork, event programs, as well as various artifacts, such as banners, ribbons, buttons, and ceremonial uniforms.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of materials pertaining to the County Longford Ladies Auxiliary, the County Longford Association, the United Irish Counties Association, and other Irish American organizations based in the greater New York City area. Materials include photographs, artwork, event programs, as well as various artifacts, such as banners, ribbons, buttons, and ceremonial uniforms.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research without restrictions.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Related Archival Materials
Archives of Irish America County Societies Collection (AIA 003)
United Irish Counties Association of New York (AIA 056)
Biographical Note
Rose Cosgrove (1908-2009) was a leading member of the County Longford Association and the County Longford Social Club of New York. Born in Dernaferst, Lough Gowna, Co. Cavan, she emigrated to New York as a young woman. Upon her arrival, she worked as a housekeeper and joined numerous Irish American social organizations. She served as the president of the Co. Longford Association from 1982-1984. Up until the last ten years of her life, Cosgrove travelled to Ireland annually.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Brigid Connolly Sullivan, Rose Cosgrove's neice, donated the materials in this collection to Glucksman Ireland House in anticipation of an exhibit in 2010. Additional donations were received at an unknown, later date. The accession number associated with this gift is 2011.002.
In March 2025, Marion Casey donated an accretion of photographs; the accession number associated with this transfer is 2025.026.
Irish Americans -- Ethnic identity.; Irish Americans -- New York (N.Y.) -- Social life and customs.; Longford (Ireland: County); Women -- New York (State) -- New York -- Societies, etc.; Irish Americans -- Social life and customs.; Irish Americans -- Societies, etc.
- Artifacts: County Longford Ladies Auxiliary hats and ribbons (Box 2)
- Artwork and Home Crafts, circa 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- "Beautiful Ireland in Verse and Picture", circa 1940-1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- "Celtic Crossing: A Celebration of Irish Heritage", undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1994-2007 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Dinner Dance Programs, 1979, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Framed Photograph Collage, undated (Box 5)
- Meeting Log Book, 1957-1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 7, Box Shared Tamiment AIAOS001, Folder 1, Box Shared Tamiment 193, Folder 5)
- Plaque, undated (Box 2)
- Ribbons, undated (Box 3, Box 4)
- United Irish Counties Association, 1979-1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)